Hello, everybody. My name is Yushan Han. I'm a physics engineer at Epic Games.
안녕하세요. 제 이름은 한유산(Yushan Han)이고, 에픽게임즈의 물리 엔지니어입니다.
In the Witcher 4 Unreal Engine tech demo, we brought series hordes to life using Chaos Flesh system.
위쳐 4 언리얼 엔진 테크 데모에서 Chaos Flesh 시스템을 활용해 Ciri의 말 ‘켈피’를 생동감 있게 구현했습니다.
And I'm excited to show you how to do that using our character email as an example.
그리고 오늘은 에밀(Emil) 캐릭터를 예시로 그 과정을 보여드리게 되어 기대됩니다.
First, make sure you download the zip file from the web page and unzip it under the content directory.
먼저, 웹페이지에서 ZIP 파일을 내려받아 프로젝트의 Content 폴더 아래에 압축을 풀어 주세요.
Now, let's make sure you have all the plugins enabled.
이제, 필요한 플러그인들이 모두 켜져 있는지 확인합시다.
First, make sure you have Chaos Flesh enabled.
먼저 Chaos Flesh 플러그인을 활성화하세요.
We're also going to need ML deformers.
그리고 ML Deformer도 필요합니다.
So make sure you have ML deformer framework and also ML deformer neural morph model enabled.
따라서 ML Deformer Framework와 ML Deformer Neural Morph Model도 켜 주세요.
Once you have all three of them enabled, make sure you restart the editor so that they're in effect.
이 세 가지 플러그인을 모두 활성화했다면, 에디터를 재시작해야 적용됩니다.
Now, let's take a look at the assets we're going to use for our character email here.
이제, 캐릭터 에셋을 확인해 보겠습니다.
Let's go into meshes.
Meshes 폴더로 들어가 보겠습니다.
First, we're going to see the skin of email.
먼저, 소체의 스킨 메시가 있습니다.
We also have muscles, skeleton, also the fat layer.
그리고 근육, 스켈레톤, 지방층(fat layer) 에셋도 있습니다.
It's a closed fat layer.
이건 닫힌 지방층(closed fat layer)입니다.
The idea is that we're going to use the animated skeleton to drive the muscles and also the fat.
구조는 애니메이션된 스켈레톤으로 근육과 지방을 구동하는 방식입니다.
And eventually transfer the deformations onto the skin so that we can train a multi-former to learn realistic deformations on the skin.
그리고 최종적으로 변형을 스킨으로 전달하여, ML Deformer가 사실적인 피부 변형을 학습하도록 하는 것이죠.
First, we have this bicep curl animation.
먼저, 이 이두근 컬(bicep curl) 애니메이션이 있습니다.
We also have a range of motion for some general movements of the character.
또, 캐릭터의 일반적인 동작 전반을 위한 가동범위(Range of Motion) 클립도 준비되어 있습니다.
In the next video, we'll start setting up muscle simulation on our character email.
다음 영상에서는 에밀 캐릭터에 근육 시뮬레이션을 설정하는 과정을 시작하겠습니다.
And we'll see here on the next video.
그럼 다음 영상에서 뵙겠습니다.